ILGWU. Ohio Kentucky Region photographs 5780/183 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU. Ohio Kentucky Region photographs
1924-1996
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/183 P
4.94 cubic feet
4.9 linear ft.
Photographs.
This collection consists of photographs transferred from the Ohio Kentucky Region records. Photographs document the activities of the regional department, including meetings, rallies, and conventions. Some photographs appear to have been used in the Ohio Kentucky Region periodical, Ohio Kentucky News.
7128080
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, April 14, 2011
EAD encoding:
Kathryn Dowgiewicz, June 06, 2013
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States, the ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. In 1995, the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) to form the Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE).
Biographical / Historical
The ILGWU had been organizing in Cleveland since its early years, and by the 1930s, the union was organizing in other parts of Ohio and Kentucky as well. The Cleveland Joint Board and Cleveland Knitgoods Council represented workers in Cleveland, and Cincinnati Joint Board represented workers in Cincinnati and parts of Kentucky. Together, these represented ILGWU members in the Ohio-Kentucky Area.
By 1977, the Ohio-Kentucky Area, which included local unions in the Ohio-Kentucky Region, Cleveland Joint Board and Knitgoods Council, and unaffiliated locals, claimed a total membership of roughly 5,500 people. In 1978, the Ohio-Kentucky Regional Office was dissolved. Local unions in Ohio became part of the Northeast and Western Pennsylvania Department to create the Northeast, Western Pennsylvania, and Ohio Department. Kentucky locals became part of the Upper South Department.
Abraham Katovsky was the ILGWU representative in Ohio from 1910 until his death 1945. Nathan Solomon was appointed Manager of the Cleveland Joint Board, a position he held until his passing in 1948. Louis Friend and Hyman Langer served short appointments, until Nicholas Kirtzman assumed leadership of the region in 1950 and stayed in that role until his death in 1963. Sam Janis was director of the regional office from 1963 until its dissolution in 1978.
Scope and Contents
The predominant theme of the photograph collection is union business, mainly exemplified by individuals seated around tables for meetings. There are group photos at meetings, conferences, and dinners, with individuals either sitting at tables or standing, and people at podiums. There are also numerous panoramic photographs of various ILGWU conventions with the delegates from the Ohio- Kentucky Region. The images also help to illustrate events of the union at the local level, with numerous parties for holidays and retirement dinners, as well as members participating in classes offered by the various locals. Several of the photographs are identified by strike, meeting or city or local, but the majority of the images remain unidentified, these are mainly of individuals or an unknown meeting or conference. Some of the photos appear to have been used in publications for the region. The collection contains different formats, such as prints and snapshots, 35mm negatives and contact sheets.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/183: ILGWU. Ohio Kentucky Region records 5780/183 AV: ILGWU. Ohio Kentucky Region audio-visual materials
Women's clothing industry -- United States.; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- United States.; Industrial relations -- United States; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. -- Ohio-Kentucky Region.
7128080
- Gertrude W. Donahey (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Untitled (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Scope and Contents
  "Your Money's Worth" graphic and negatives
- Untitled (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Includes: meeting, Jay Mazur, Sol Hoffman
- OK News [Ohio-Kentucky], 1963 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  August-September 1963
- OK News [Ohio-Kentucky], 1961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  November-December 1961
- Sam Janis (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Untitled (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Includes: photo from Cleveland Plain Dealer, women in line at State Probation and Parole
- Untitled (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Includes: Stephen M. Young for Senate; members; healthcare; meetings; office; Ohio-Kentucky delegation to convention, 1959; William Corrigan; leafletting at Christmas
- January-February 1962 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Miscellaneous 1964 [Mike Frankel] (Box 1, Folder 10)
- [portraits] (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Includes: John Gilligan, Clifford Brown, Gertrude Donahey, Joseph O'Neill, Howard Metzenbach, Richard Celeste, Frank Abbuzze [sp?], Tony Hall
- Mike Frankel (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Picnic (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Local 481 news (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Untitled, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Includes: [meetings of retirees?]
- Untitled (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Untitled (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Includes: meetings, parties, protest against imports, retirees
- Kirtzman portraits, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  April 1961
- OK News [Ohio-Kentucky], 1961 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  April-May 1961
- "Yoshke" celebration, camp Vladek, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- OK [Ohio-Kentucky] conference meeting, Camp Vladek, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Summer 1954
- Glasgow, Kentucky, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Cleveland Knitgoods retirement dinner for Caroline Moebelt, President of Local 298, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  January 14, 1960
- Toledo charter signing (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Serbin strikers, Fayetteville, Ohio, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Talon Manufacturing (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Convention delegates at airport, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Also includes: strike at Frisch Knitting Mills, Cleveland, Ohio
- Right-to-Work meeting, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  April 17, 1958
- Bond meeting (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Untitled (Box 2, Folder 11)
  [Sol Hoffman?]
- Ohio-Kentucky Region delegates to convention, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Untitled (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Bloomfield signing (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Convention, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Untitled (Box 2, Folder 16)
- OK [Ohio-Kentucky] conference (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Local 29 retirement party, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  March 29, 1960
- Kirtzman and FDR, Jr., Social Security 25th anniversary, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  October 16, 1960
- Camp Vladek (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Corrigan testimnonial membership in ILGWU (Box 2, Folder 21)
- [Charter] (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Stephen Young (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Local 526 Executive Board at dinner for severance pay, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  February 1, 1957
- Local 44 retirement party, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  April 2, 1960
- Retirement, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Installation meeting, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  March 15, 1956
- Convention, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Convention, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Untitled (Box 2, Folder 30)
- ILGWU seminar at Circle Camp, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  August 2, 1960
- [Protest against anti-union legislation] (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Untitled (Box 2, Folder 33)
  Includes: Earlene Duvall of Local 481, Glasgow, Kentucky, and Dorothy Rhodes of Local 545, Woodsfield, Ohio
- Convention, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Untitled (Box 2, Folder 35)
  Includes: contact sheet
- Kirtzman, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Spain trip, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Untitled (Box 2, Folder 38)
  Includes: contact sheets and negatives
- Untitled (Box 2, Folder 39)
  Includes: contact sheet and negatives
- Untitled (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Untitled (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Untitled (Box 2, Folder 42)
  Includes: meetings
- Untitled (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Untitled (Box 2, Folder 44)
  Includes: performance
- Union Label, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- AFL-CIO meetings, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Untitled (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Includes: meeting
- Learning Lab (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Untitled (Box 3, Folder 5)
- [Portraits] (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Negatives (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Includes: civil rights conference, 1970; Ohio AFL-CIO Convention, 1970; ILGWU Building; Marietta Cusano P-B retiree; import rally, 1984
- Sharon's quilt (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Retirees (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Untitled (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Includes: meetings, Nicholas Kirtzman, and Kirtzman obituary by Michael Frankel
- Kentucky, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  Includes: group photos with names
- Christmas party, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Untitled (Box 3, Folder 13)
  Includes: Local 795, Nicholas Kirtzman with David Dubinsky (negatives), happy birthday graphic
- Untitled (Box 3, Folder 14)
  Includes: party
- Untitled (Box 3, Folder 15)
  Includes: meetings, protest against apartheid
- Untitled (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Opus 1970 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  Includes: portraits
- Voter registration (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Untitled (Box 3, Folder 19)
  Includes:Gilligan supporters
- American Labor ORT, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  Los Angeles, California, September 18, 1954
- Opening of ILGWU headquarters (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Untitled (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Untitled (Box 3, Folder 23)
  Includes: Kentucky State AFL-CIO, meetings, Union Label
- Airview of Cleveland, ILGWU Headquarters clinic (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Kentucky conference, picture with "Happy" Chandler, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  January 1955
- Untitled negatives (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Untitled contact sheet and negatives (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Untitled contact sheet and negatives (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Includes: class
- Untitled contact sheet and negatives (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Includes: party, people in shop
- Arbitration (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Untitled contact sheets and negatives (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Includes: Christmas party, retiree [?] trip
- Retirees' Club Meeting, Judith Winemann, Director of Retiree Services Department, New York setup "Friendly Visitors Program", 1992 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  March 11, 1992
- Ohio District Council meeting, Holiday Inn-Hudson, elect officer, write resolutions for ILGWU convention, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  March 14, 1992
- Piqua negotiating committee (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Untited photographs and negatives (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Untitled contact sheets and negatives (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Untitled (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Untitled (Box 4, Folder 13)
  Includes: recreation
- Untitled contact sheets and negatives (Box 4, Folder 14)
- [Unity House] (Box 4, Folder 15)
- [Ohio District Council meeting] (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Untitled contact sheets and negatives (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Classes (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Untitled contact sheets and negatives (Box 4, Folder 19)
  Includes: meetings and trip to Sotus Candies
- Shop reporters (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Untitled (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Untitled contact sheet and negatives (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Classes, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Other Ohio, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Retirees' trip, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  July 17, 1979
- Untitled contact sheets and negatives (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Retirees' indoor dinner, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  August 1984
- [Ohio District Council meeting] (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Fire drills in memory of Triangle fire victims, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  Cleveland Knitting Mills, March 24, 1992; K-Mart Apparel, March 26, 1992; Ohio Knitting Mills, March 26, 1992
- Untitled (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Ohio District Council, Holiday Inn-Hudson, election, officers write resolutions to ILGWU convention, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Untitled contact sheet and negatives (Box 4, Folder 32)
- [Rally to protect indigent care in Ohio] (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Untitled photographs and negatives, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Includes: leafletting, Judy Hathaway, Patty Chine, Mary Ann Gould, Joy Friend, Viola Streight, Fran Green (Local 590, UNITE), Kevin Plank (Under Armour), Sal Fasciana (UP/Plan Manager, Triple A in the USA)
- [Labor union fair] (Box 5, Folder 2)
- [Protest at Kmart] (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Includes sign, "Fight Discrimination: Boycott Kmart!"
- [Retirees?] (Box 5, Folder 4)
- [Rally to protect the indigent, Ohio AFL-CIO convention], 1996 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- [Ohio District Council meeting] (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Untitled (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Includes: speaker with group
- Untitled (Box 5, Folder 8)
- [Ohio District Council meeting] (Box 5, Folder 9)
- [Christmas party] (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Untitled (Box 5, Folder 11)
  Includes: dinner
- Untitled (Box 5, Folder 12)
- [Ohio District Council meeting] (Box 5, Folder 13)
- [Ohio District Council meeting] (Box 5, Folder 14)
- [UNITE meeting] (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Untitled (Box 5, Folder 16)
- [Candlelight vigil, meeting] (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Untitled (Box 5, Folder 18)
  Includes: various speakers at podium, meeting
- [UNITE meeting] (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Kmart CPR classes, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- [Meeting at Holiday Inn-Hudson] (Box 5, Folder 21)
  1992?
- Untitled (Box 5, Folder 22)
  Includes: swearing in, speakers against NAFTA, convention, meetings, Union Label
- Untitled (Box 5, Folder 23)
  Includes: woman cutting cake
- Untitled (Box 5, Folder 24)
  Includes: office, Christmas party
- Untitled photographs, contact sheets, and negatives (Box 5, Folder 25)
  Includes: Lion Knit Negotiating Team, Unity House
- Untitled (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Untitled (Box 6, Folder 2)
  Includes: Christmas party
- Retirees and strikes (Box 6, Folder 3)
  Includes: Josephine Kucera, P.B. retiree, June 26; speaker on food stamps
- Untitled (Box 6, Folder 4)
  Includes: Barbara Janis, Coalition of Labor Union Women; letter from Mary Jung to Bill Sullivan regarding the Equal Rights Amendment (ERA)
- Untitled (Box 6, Folder 5)
  Includes: election or raffle [?]
- Photographs uned in November 1978 paper (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Untitled contact sheet and negatives (Box 6, Folder 7)
  Includes: meeting at Sheraton Hotel, Columbus, Ohio
- Untitled contact sheets and negatives (Box 6, Folder 8)
  Includes: classes, office
- Raffles, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Miscellaneous photographs and negatives (Box 6, Folder 10)
  Includes: party; Brownsville; meeting; Christmas party, 1970; Learning Lab, Elizabeth Wright, Joint Board meeting, self defense class, retirees Christmas party, Kentucky December 1969 meeting, Cincinnati Christmas party, retirees
- Untitled contact sheet and negatives (Box 6, Folder 11)
  Includes: class [?]
- Untitled contact sheet and negatives (Box 6, Folder 12)
  Includes: party, performance
- Civil Rights conference, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Untitled contact sheet and negatives (Box 6, Folder 14)
  Includes: retiree Christmas party [?]
- Untitled contact sheets and negatives (Box 6, Folder 15)
  Includes: parties
- Easter [imports] demonstration, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Staff, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- ILGWU (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Untitled (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Miscellaneous, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  Includes: Convention, 1962; Union Label; Wayne County Central Labor Union; Bobbie Brooks building; Christmas; meetings
- Governor Gilligan with ILGWU members (Box 6, Folder 21)
  Includes: Shirley Stevenson of New Philadelphia, Mary LeGlise of Strasburg, Joan Hutras of Dover, and Ruth and Donna Burns both of New Philadelphia
- Columbus Workers Comp. meeting (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Columbus District Council meeting (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Bobbie Brooks contract talks (Box 6, Folder 24)
  Includes: Al Gariula, Wilbur Daniels, Joseph Good, Buzz Rosenfeld (company)
- Untitled contact sheets and negatives (Box 6, Folder 25)
  Includes: meeting, party
- Untitled contact sheets and negatives (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Untitled contact sheets and negatives (Box 7, Folder 2)
  Includes: political campaigning, supporters [?]
- Untitled contact sheet and negatives (Box 7, Folder 3)
  Includes: worker in shop
- Untitled contact sheet, negatives and prints (Box 7, Folder 4)
  Includes: group photographs
- Untitled contact sheet and negatives (Box 7, Folder 5)
  Includes: office [?]
- Untitled (Box 7, Folder 6)
  Includes: UNITE, Columbus Cancer Clinic
- Untitled contact sheet and negatives (Box 7, Folder 7)
  Includes: office
- Untitled contact sheets (Box 7, Folder 8)
  Includes: panel discussion, meeting
- Untitled contact sheet and negatives (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Untitled contact sheet and negatives (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Ohio District Council (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Union Label display (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Untitled contact sheet and negatives (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Untitled (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Untitled contact sheet and negatives (Box 7, Folder 15)
  Includes: stained glass window
- Untitled, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  Includes: meeting, Canada Steamship Lines poster
- Untitled contact sheet (Box 7, Folder 17)
  Includes: meeting outside building, office
- Untitled contact sheet and negatives (Box 7, Folder 18)
  Includes: panel discussion, group photographs
- Untitled (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Untitled (Box 7, Folder 20)
  Includes: class, training [?]
- Untitled (Box 7, Folder 21)
  Includes: self defense class [?]
- Untitled contact sheets and negatives (Box 7, Folder 22)
  Includes: speakers for Howard Metzenbaum, meetings
- Ohio District Council (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Untitled, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  Includes: packing presents in shop, ILGWU "On the Move"
- Coalition of Labor Union Women (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Credit Union meetings (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Untitled (Box 7, Folder 27)
  Includes: meeting, group photographs
- Trial sheet with new camera (Box 7, Folder 28)
  Includes: office and staff
- Untitled contact sheet and negatives (Box 7, Folder 29)
  Includes: meeting, office
- United Labor Agency (Box 7, Folder 30)
- Untitled (Box 7, Folder 31)
  Includes: meeting regarding NAFTA and health alliance [?], Ohio District Council
- Portraits (Box 7, Folder 32)
- Untitled (Box 7, Folder 33)
  Includes: on strike at Frick Franklin Incorporated, protesting Richman Brothers
- Political (Box 7, Folder 34)
  Includes: Stokes supporters; meetings with Vanik, Stokes, Stanton on minimum wage, 1972
- Ohio District Council (Box 7, Folder 35)
- Retirees Club trip, Put N Bay, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  Negatives, August 20, 1996
- Untitled (Box 7, Folder 37)
  Includes: meeting at Holiday Inn, Hudson, Ohio
- Untitled (Box 7, Folder 38)
- Meeting/presentation (Box 8, Folder 1)
- [Photographs removed for conservation] (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Cleveland 1975 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  Strikes: "Save American Jobs," "Stop Imports"
- Elections-Cincinnati, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Election (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Cleveland AFL-CIO Labor Day Parade prize winner, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Judy Bond Campaign, leafleting at Easter (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Committee on Work Standards, ILGWU 31st Convention, Atlantic City, May 23-June 1, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Misc. Groups and Meetings, 1944-1953 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  Cleveland Joint Board; Committee on Officers Reports, ILGWU 28th Convention, Chicago May 18-26, 1953; Ohio and Kentucky Delegation 28th ILGWU Convention; Cleveland Delegation at the 25th ILGWU Convention, Boston June 1944
- Ohio and Kentucky Region Delegation, ILGWU 31st Convention, Atlantic City May 23-June 1, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Panoramic group shot (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Delegation at the 28th Convention of the ILGWU, Chicago May 18-26, 1953 (Box 9OP, Folder 1)
- 30th Convention of the ILGWU, Miami Beach May 11-19, 1959 (Box 9OP, Folder 2)
- Golden Jubilee Convention of the ILGWU, Atlantic City May 23-June 1, 1950 (Box 9OP, Folder 3)
- 34th Convention of the ILGWU Miami Beach, May 6-14, 1971 (Box 9OP, Folder 4)
- 26th Convention of the ILGWU, Cleveland June 16-27, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Second Session of the 28th Convention of the ILGWU, Chicago May 18-26 1953 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- 29th Convention of the ILGWU, Atlantic City May 10-18, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Dedication Banquet Ohio State Federation of Labor, January 21, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Opening Session 25th Convention of the ILGWU Boston, May 29, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Delegates at the 25th Convention of the ILGWU, Boston, May 31, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Printzess Banquet Honoring Arthur C. Hoffman by Fellow Workers, March 7, 1924 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Ohio & Kentucky Delegation at the 28th ILGWU Convention, Chicago May 18-26, 1953 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Committee on Education at the 28th ILGWU Convention, Chicago May 18-26, 1953 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- 30th ILGWU Convention, Miami Beach May 11-19, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 9)